Venezuela crisis: Maduro aides agreed he had to go, US says
The US suggests loyalists of the Venezuelan president backtracked on a promise to oust him.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-48114826
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 21:49:16 GMT
On the ground of Venezuela's uprising
Juan Guaid? has called on the military to support him in ousting President Nicol?s Maduro.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-latin-america-48110315
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 16:05:23 GMT
Japan's new Emperor Naruhito succeeds father Akihito
Emperor Naruhito formally takes up the Chrysanthemum throne a day after his father's abdication.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-48101637
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 20:25:14 GMT
White House to designate Muslim Brotherhood terrorist organisation
The move against the Middle East group would prompt wide-ranging sanctions.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48111594
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 21:13:38 GMT
Dutch WW2 Queen 'considered Nazi swap for Belgian royals'
As World War Two neared an end, Dutch Queen Wilhelmina was asked to help save Belgium's royal family.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-48104258
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 15:31:52 GMT
Italian teen gang 'tortured pensioner' - eight held
An elderly man who died near Taranto was beaten up repeatedly by a gang, prosecutors say.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-48104267
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:04:21 GMT
France harassment law hands out 447 fines in first months
France hands out 447 on-the-spot fines for sexual harassment in the first months of a new law.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-48104247
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 09:21:24 GMT
Mozambique cyclone: Humanitarian situation is 'life-threatening'
More funds are needed to deal with the life threatening situation, aid organisation says.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-48096148
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 10:52:51 GMT
China sentences second Canadian to death
Fan Wei is the second Canadian to be given the death penalty in China amid a diplomatic row.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-china-48104607
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 18:38:39 GMT
Three killed in Hawaii tour helicopter crash
The fiery crash left a trail of debris on a busy residential street as bystanders attempted to help.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48095763
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 16:31:40 GMT
Trump sues Deutsche Bank and Capital One over Democrat subpoenas
The lawsuit aims to stop Deutsche Bank and Capital One from handing over his records to Congress.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48102647
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 08:01:44 GMT
'Yeti footprints': Indian army mocked over claim
Its claim to have discovered footprints of the "mythical beast" prompts derision on social media.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-india-48101717
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 06:48:39 GMT
Akihito: The Japanese emperor with the human touch
Emperor Akihito will be remembered as the man who began the modernisation of Japan's Chrysanthemum Throne.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-48093668
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:08:55 GMT
Is plant burger firm Beyond Meat really worth $1.5bn?
The BBC gives Beyond Meat's key product - its vegan burger - a try ahead of its stock market listing.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48110704
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 18:30:50 GMT
Spying whales and other undercover animals
The list of animals used in espionage is longer than you might think.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/newsbeat-48105437
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 12:12:00 GMT
Jeopardy: How a pro gambler 'cracked' a US game show
Sports bettor James Holzhauer's unusual strategy is paying off as he crushes Jeopardy records.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48032235
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:24:59 GMT
'We are students thanks to South Africa's #FeesMustFall protests'
What has changed since mass protests led South Africa to announce free education for poor university students?
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-47952787
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:12:23 GMT
How tech is bringing Israelis and Palestinians together
Young people on either side of a decades-old conflict seldom meet, but tech is building bridges.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/business-48053200
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:08:17 GMT
Sri Lanka attacks: Where else in the world have face coverings been banned?
Following the Sri Lankan ban, BBC Reality Check looks at other countries that have imposed either a partial or complete ban on face coverings
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-48092641
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:24:53 GMT
Sports Illustrated features first burkini girl
Halima Aden becomes the first model to wear a burkini in Sports Illustrated's swimsuit issue.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/48071948
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 18:17:54 GMT
Japan's emperor abdicates the throne
Emperor Akihito is the first emperor to abdicate in over 200 years.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-asia-48101024
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 11:16:06 GMT
'Our water pollution is a cancer'
"Waterkeeper" Nabil Musa fights Iraq's water crisis, which he calls the country's gravest threat yet.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-48097091
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:00:29 GMT
Honduras protesters clash with riot police
Anger over feared privatisation of the education and health sectors spills over into street battles.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/48110844
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 14:17:01 GMT
'Russian spy whale'
A beluga whale was found with suspicious equipment off Norway's coast
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-48100700
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 22:05:47 GMT
Mozambique: Cyclone Kenneth aftermath leaves 200,000 at risk
Lebo Diseko reports as rain continues to hamper aid efforts in Mozambique in the wake of Cyclone Kenneth.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-africa-48113961
Tue, 30 Apr 2019 17:26:59 GMT
Syrian refugees: The humanitarian magician who makes smiles
Jamie Balfour-Paul has a mission to bring smiles and fun to Syrian refugee children.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/uk-england-oxfordshire-48092919
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 23:03:10 GMT
Europe and nationalism: A country-by-country guide
Ahead of the May European elections, a country-by-country guide to the advance of nationalist parties.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-europe-36130006
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 10:01:11 GMT
Anna Sorokin: The trial of New York's fake heiress
A woman who pretended to be a wealthy heiress to swindle high society New York is convicted of multiple charges.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-47741923
Fri, 26 Apr 2019 08:42:55 GMT
How the US military's opium war in Afghanistan was lost
The US has spent $1.5m a day fighting the opium war in Afghanistan. Why is business still booming?
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-47861444
Thu, 25 Apr 2019 20:20:40 GMT
Yaba: The cheap synthetic drug convulsing a nation
Yaba, a mix of methamphetamine and caffeine, is wreaking havoc in Bangladesh, and hundreds of people have died in "crossfire" incidents involving police.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/stories-48041414
Wed, 24 Apr 2019 23:30:58 GMT
Edge of the Knife: The film in a language only 20 people speak
How the film Edge of the Knife could help save Haida, an indigenous language on Canada's west coast.
https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-48028970
Mon, 29 Apr 2019 06:59:29 GMT
